Chicago, IL | (312) 282-0382 | timsmail@yahoo.com | www.linkedin.com/in/timprokuski

Overview

Results oriented leader with experience building and leading teams which produce relevant products. Ability to visualize a product, define requirements, set direction, specify key decisions, communicate effectively, participate as a strong team player and mentor, perform software architecture and development, and deliver final products. Experienced in delivering products, under pressure, on time, and following best practices. Builds and maintains strong relationships which offer a wealth of resources to reference for advice and perspective. Curious and always striving to learn personally and professionally. A diverse and inclusive person who looks for the best in people and their ideas. Strives to build effective and relevant products which matter.

Technical Skills & Methodologies

Frameworks and Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, CI/CD methods

Technical Skills: Experienced in architecting software products and enterprise level system integrations. Highly experienced developer in Java, Spring, web services, SQL, middle tier technologies, Jira, Git, Linux. Knowledgeable in front end UI/UX development, data storage designs, application of commercial software packages, Azure cloud services, big data and data virtualization.

Experience

Health Care Service Corporation - BCBS (www.hcsc.com) - Chicago, IL IT Product Manager, Member Eligibility

2019 – Present

Coordinated and managed the transition to a big data eligibility services platform responsible for providing over 800 monthly vendor integration data feeds and real time web service integration capabilities. Coordinated vendor health care data integrations. Applied Agile methodologies to manage distributed and diverse teams in delivering new products and system enhancements.

- Managed the transition of member eligibility data services, for 17+ million members, to a large-scale data lake with data virtualization and Azure cloud services targeting a 40% plus reduction in new development time and costs, higher data accuracy, and the consolidation and standardization of source of truth data elements.
- Specified and led the implementation of web-services real-time integration with the HCSC primary pharmacy vendor which decreased a members update latency from three days down to approximately three minutes.
- Designed and led the implementation of a member eligibility status web service providing to external vendors the benefits of real-time member status verifications, increased data accuracy, and the elimination of large scale and expensive coordinated batch synchronization processes.
- Managed product direction, ongoing support and maintenance, cross product impact analysis across the enterprise, negotiated
 external vendor integration requirements, managed internal consulting resources for product development.
- Participated in and influenced architecture decisions, product specifications, product presentation to relevant business teams, and coordinated cross team testing efforts.

CAI - Computer Aid Inc (www.cai.io) - Chicago, IL

2018 - 2019

(Consultant) Software Development Consultant for the City of Chicago

Developed, enhanced, and supported the cashiering system for the City of Chicago.

- Developed new functionality and system fixes for a JEE based application utilizing Java, JEE, Spring, Hibernate, Oracle, REST web services (Spring), Git, JBoss EAP.
- Collaborated with the City of Chicago accounting department to enhance system functionalities, fix bugs, specify new functionality, and provide product support and issue/ticket resolution.

W.W. Grainger (www.grainger.com) - Chicago, IL

2015 - 2016

(Consultant) Software Development Consultant on Grainger.com

Developed Web and JEE based software services for a large-scale order processing system within a middle tier integration layer which helped to reduce web site response times with increased application performance.

- Built middle tier integrations with web services, JMS queues, Cassandra persistence modules, and JSP/HTML maintenance screens, for a large-scale order processing web site
- JBoss EAP, Java, Cassandra, Git, Splunk, extensive JVM performance tuning for java and Cassandra services.

Brandom Construction - Chicago, IL

2012 - 2018

Manager and Product Delivery Lead for a private construction development company

Defined product vision, features, requirements, determined and managed project budgets, managed construction efforts, sub-contractors, permitting requirements and approvals, and overall delivery of new residential and commercial real estate products.

- Managed the acquisition of over \$7.1 million in real estate which was resold for a gross value of over \$14.4 million with a near 30% net profit margin after renovation or new build.
- Delivered 31 new and newly renovated real estate projects with a 100% profitability ratio.
- For commercial and residential customers, tailored project scope, administered budget and schedule control, resources solicitation and procurement, job cost accounting and cash flow, and completed projects within scope, time, and budget.
- Applied for and secured approvals and final sign offs of all permitting concerns within the City of Chicago and many local villages across many projects.

Seaton Corporation (trueblue) (www.trueblue.com) - $\operatorname{Chicago}$, IL

Software Architect and Developer - Staff Management

Architected and built a custom applicant tracking/management and staff scheduling application managing annually approximately 4.3 million staff and applicants. Application is based on Java, J2EE, and Oracle.

- Extensive system architecture and development of new functionalities to enhance applicant onboarding, scheduling, and time management, to significantly reduce the recruitment to work time.
- Re-architectures which provided adoption of dynamic Web 2.0 functionalities, web services, performance enhancements, and streamlining of coding patterns.

UBS Investment Bank (www.ubs.com), Chicago, IL

2007 - 2008

(Consultant) Software Developer - Pinpoint Trading Application

• Developed new interfaces for the Pinpoint Trading application, led adoption of new Java based technologies, built a multithreaded task scheduling system for submission of scheduled and ad-hoc jobs. Java, HTML/Javascript, SQL technologies.

Cardinal Health (www.cardinalhealth.com), McGaw Park, IL

1996 - 2003 and 2006 - 2007

(Consultant) Manager/Architect/Developer - Healthcare Manufacturing, Distribution, and Transportation systems

Consulted, managed, and developed numerous large-scale systems for various groups of this top global healthcare and pharmaceutical supply company. Performed leadership, application architecture, and development roles based on the client and project expectations.

- Designed, managed, and led the development of a custom chargeback system integrated into an enterprise-wide SAP ERP
 implementation. This system recouped over one billion dollars annually of revenue return with an additional 50 million in
 retroactive chargebacks recouped thru additional system enhancements.
- Designed and developed web-based applications which optimized the scheduling and management of logistics personnel and equipment, freight sharing optimization, and included integration into an i2 Transportation Manger installation.
- Defined and collaborated on the development and build out of a large-scale Oracle Data Warehouse with a universe designed
 to provide efficient analysis of data related to product pricing and margin trends allowing the business to identify and
 optimize variances.
- Built an internet storefront which provided web integration into the backend enterprise order processing system.
- Developed an enterprise B2B ecommerce framework which provided business partner integration via XML documents. The
 system effectively linked the supply chains and ordering systems between business partners allowing them to communicate
 and do business in real-time in a flexible and automated manner.
- Built a rules-based expert system which embedded the domain expert knowledge into a flexible system of coded rules which
 were then analyzed across multiple data sources to initiate business specific actions. The system automated the decision
 support processes, cut down the time of order dispute resolutions, and increased the accuracy of the resolutions.
- Over a ten-year period, I consulted and provided development and management leadership on many projects while building a strong reputation for delivering quality products on time for a global fortune 50 company.

JC Whitney (www.carparts.com/jc-whitney), Chicago, IL

2004 - 2005

Architect/Technical Product Manager for jcwhitney.com and installpro.net

- Lead a team of 20 resources in developing a new startup web application which offered local custom product installations for
 jcwhitney.com products. This add-on service increased the sales conversion rates by offering customers a unique and
 convenient service which eliminated the DIY complexities of installing sold products.
- Integrated installation offerings into jewhitney.com based on geographical location, product categories, and installer network
- Managed consultants and employees, mentored junior developers, and reported directly to CTO.

Oracle Corporation (www.oracle.com), U.S. and abroad

2003 - 2004

Principal Consultant/J2EE Architect - Client Solutions Development

Designed and developed Java/Oracle based solutions for multiple clients domestically and internationally. Applied RUP, UML, and OO design methodologies and rapid development processes to build efficient and modern software products.

- Participated in a USAF modernization effort by overseeing the reengineering of an existing USAF logistics management system into a J2EE web-based application aimed at modernizing and increasing the efficiency of the functionalities.
- Developed a prototype RFID package tracking application for a global shipping company which helped them evaluate the capabilities of the current technology and measure the efficiencies of introducing RFID into their tracking processes.

Cardinal Health (www.cardinalhealth.com), McGaw Park, IL

1996 - 2003

*Refer to above summary of Cardinal Health tenure

Various full time software development positions while pursuing my M.S. degree, Chicago, IL

1990 - 1996

Focused on development roles using C/C++, client server, SQL, technologies.

- Consultant to Baxter Healthcare Modification, new development, and support of a large-scale just-in-time inventory management and supply system. Based on client server technologies this system was the gateway into hospital supply centers by providing a value-added service which allowed Baxter to essentially manage a customers supply chain of products.
- Blue Cross Blue Shield Association Technical Consultant
- Consultant to Arthur Anderson (Accenture) Developer
- Sourcemark Services Consulting Group Developer

Education

- **Depaul University** M.S. Computer Science
- University of Illinois at Chicago B.A. Criminal Justice/Statistics

2009 - 2014